and the answer is we will use a return
address stack which is a separate
predictor dedicated to predicting
function returns the way it works
is that we have a small stack in
hardware
with a pointer
as we execute the program when we have a
function call
we will push the return address in this
case one two three
zero is the address of the call so one
two three four would be the return
address to the return address stack f
move the pointer
in the function when we encounter the
return instruction
we will pop
from this return address stack and use
the one two three four to return and in
that case get the correct target address
now our pointer is here we don't really
have to delete this entry because the
pointer being here means that it's free
next when we reach the next place where
the function is called from we will save
the return address in this case one two
five 4 onto the return address stack the
function executes when we see the return
instruction
we pop the return address and we again
predict correctly so why is this a
predictor why not just use the actual
stack of the program
well because this predictor needs to be
on chip very close to where the rest of
the branch prediction is happening and
needs to be very very small so unlike
your traditional stack
where you will push something onto the
stack call another function from there
call a nested function and you can do
that many many times until you run out
of memory in this particular case we can
have a very small hardware structure so
that it can make a prediction very
quickly like in one cycle thus it can
only have a limited number of entries so
what happens when we exceed the size of
the ras
let's say we have only four entries
let's say that we call a function we
call another one we call another one we
call another one and now
the question is what do we do
so if our ass is full what do we do
there are really two choices one
don't push anything pretty much preserve
what we already have on our wrist so
that we don't overwrite
anything
the other choice
is once we have filled these four
entries just wrap around and keep
filling them if we call more functions